We are going to be discussing about mirrored volume and rate 5.
So what is a mirrored volume?
A mirrored volume is a 4-tolerance volume that indicates your data on two or more physical
disks.
A mirrored volume provides redundancy by simultaneously writing the same data onto two or
more separate mirrors that reside on different disks.
So let's try to create a mirrored volume from our disk management.
So from this one it means just right click, you can see I have several disks here.
So what you want to do?
I want to call it confat this disk, visit this to dynamic disk.
So let me just select and convert this as well to dynamic disk.
And then I'm going to select all the convats, all this disk to dynamic disk.
So able to actually use the mirrored or mirrored volume or rate 5, you definitely need
a dynamic disk.
So what you need to do is right click, and here you can see we have the new mirrored
follow.
So let's click Nest.
And we're going to actually select one disk and then click Add.
So now we're going to see Nest, we can call this, they give this a little E and then click
Nest.
And then we're going to decide to just call this DATSAS and then perform a quick format.
Click Nest and finish.
Clicking finish is going to actually create a new volume.
But mind you, you can see it says here we have DATSAS, you see we see have 16 megabytes
on our located.
So what happens is this, so we now have just 10 gigabytes of space and we created used
to this which of course between the gigabytes.
But now you don't have a disk available.
So the information has been written to both disks at the same time.
So if, for example, one of these disks, something could go wrong, go wrong, you see
have a separate disk available to be able to recover your information.
So now let's discuss about RAID 5, so RAID 5 is a redundant array of independent disk
configuration that uses disk striping with parity.
Because data and parity are striped, stripped, it will be across all of the disks.
No single disk is a bottleneck, it's a bottleneck.
So striping also allows you to control data in case of a disk failure.
So the RAID 5 helps you to attribute parity, it also helps in redo, dancing, but mind
you, you need three or more disks to be able to create a RAID 5 disk.
So what I'm going to do right now is I will see how about three disks are available.
What are the same time?
I can decide to just click and then delete the reward volume we've created in this testing
environment.
And then decide to create a RAID 5 for the vehicle.
So we have the option called new RAID 5 for the load.
So let me just click Nest and then we can decide to select this.
You can see we have option to select multiple disks as well.
So let me just click Nest.
I'm going to call this the I and then Nest, and let me just call this, let's say we need
to actually copy software, I'm going to perform a quick format and click Finish.
And it's going to actually says the operations that I'm going to visit this to dynamic disk
if the disk have not been converted.
And here we go.
I'm going to say Nest.
You can see we have some disks that we're not going to get.
So let me just click Nest and our disk is being created.
Here we go, we can see right now we just created our RAID 5 volume.
So that's actually showing all the color there.
So if I open file explorer, you can see we have our RAID 5.
So it combines, you can see we have about 40 gigabytes of disk.
So it combines and I use one, two, three, four, five.
And here you can see what it's actually showing all those 40 gigabytes.
So which means that the data has been strived to all the disks that are available.
So when something goes wrong, you can also look at all very this failure, you still have
the ability to use one of those disks to recover your files.